<resources>
<string name="ringtone" >
<![CDATA[
<h1 class="western">Ringtone</h1>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Select which
ringtone to play for an alarm or notification and for how many
seconds.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Minutes
deactivated</b>: If a low or high glucose level continues, the alarm
will not immediately go off again. You can specify after how many
minutes the alarm should be generated again if the condition
continues.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Sound</b>: make
sound.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Default</b>: use
default sound.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Select</b>:
Select a ringtone. On some Samsung phone the preinstalled ringtone
picker app crashes, so you have to install a different ringtone app
that can be used by other apps, for example:
<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.centralparkapps.ringo.ringtones">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.centralparkapps.ringo.ringtones</a></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Vibrate</b>:
Vibrate</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Disturb</b>: Also
generate sound when &quot;<i>Do not Disturb</i>&quot; is on. If
Juggluco doesn\'t have the required permission for this, you will be
directed to an Android settings screen to give Juggluco this
permission. By switching on &quot;<i>Do not Disturb</i>&quot; and
pressing <i>Play,</i><span style="font-variant: normal"> </span><span style="font-variant: normal"><span style="font-style: normal">you
can test whether alarms will work during </span></span><i>&quot;Do
not Disturb&quot;.</i></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Flash</b>:
Smartphones with torch flashlight have the option to flash for the
same number of seconds. Handy in case ringtones are not allowed and
there is no clear policy concerning flashlights.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">On sites like
stackoverflow.com it is sometimes claimed that some smartphones crash
when using Flash light without camera permission, if that is the case
you can turn on Camera permission.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="reminders" >
<![CDATA[
<h1 class="western">Reminders</h1>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Reminders remind you
if you haven\'t entered a certain amount within a certain time
interval.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">By pressing <b>NEW</b>
you can add a new reminder.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Specify begin and
end time of the time period, within which you should enter the
specified amount under the specified label.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">If end time is
reached the program checks if you have entered at least this amount
with the specified label after the begin time. If you didn\'t
register, a notification is shown and a ringtone played.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">For example if you
specify:</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><i>Levemir 6.0</i></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><i>21:30 - 23:55</i></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">You will be reminded
after 23:55 if you didn\'t specify at least 6 units of Levemir after
21:30 the same day.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Already specified
reminders are shown in a list. Touch to edit.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">If everything goes
well, reminders also work after reboot of Android without the user
having to start Juggluco. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">On some Huawei
devices, you need to specify that you allow a program to be started
at boot. This is done under Android Settings -&gt; Battery -&gt; App
launch. Here you select <i>Manually managed</i> for Juggluco so that
<i>Auto-Launch</i> and <i>Run in Background</i> are on. This is also
necessary for loss of signal alarms to work after reboot without the
user starting Juggluco.</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="connectionoverview" >
<![CDATA[
<h1>Mirror</h1>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">Send
data to or receive data from another device. You can connect to an
android device running Juggluco</span> <span lang="en-US">to display
data the same way as here.</span> <span lang="en-US">After receiving
the scan data, the mirror device can also contact with the sensor via
Bluetooth. To make sure that only one of the devices contacts with
the sensor, &quot;</span><span lang="en-US"><i>Sensor via Bluetooth</i></span><span lang="en-US">&quot;
is turned off automatically when Stream values arrive via IP/TCP.</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">On this screen,
after <i>wlan</i><i>,</i> the local wlan IP of this device is shown,
you should specify this on the other device on you home network you
are connecting to (or your modem if connecting remotely).</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">After <i>Port,</i>
you can change the TCP port this app is listening on for connections.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">By clicking <i><b>Add
connection</b></i> you can specify with which hosts to connect and
how to connect.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">A reliable network
connection is on Android disrupted by all kinds of battery
optimizations and background restrictions, pressing <b>Doze mode</b>
helps you change that.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">If Juggluco
functions as a Mirror app (receiving glucose values from another
device running Juggluco), you can press <b>Alarms</b> to get to a
dialog where you can specify low and high glucose alarms and related
notifications.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Don\'t change
amounts: </b>If the app receives amounts of medication, food and
sport data from this app running on another device, you shouldn\'t add
or modify these same information here. Checking this makes it
impossible. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Sync</b> sends
new data to a connected device if available or asks for new data. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Reinit</b>:
Closes existing and creates a new connection.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Wifi</b> (only on
WearOS): Use WIFI instead of TCP over Bluetooth for the connection
between phone and watch. This is normally not needed when the phone
has an external connection (WIFI or Mobile Data). This option can be
used in the rare circumstance that the phone doesn\'t have an external
connection and there is a portable hotspot on the phone to which the
watch is connected. The makers of WearOS think that turning on WIFI
will lead to large increases in battery usage; I can not substantiate
this. Anyway, the connection between phone and watch is much more
stable when the phone has an external connection and WIFI on the
watch is turned off.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Existing connections
are shown in a list, the label, the IP port and month, day and time
of the last successful sync are shown. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">How the connection
is used is abbreviated as follows:</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">n: amounts (numbers)</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">s: scans</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">b: stream
(bluetooth)</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">r: receive</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">For more information
on Mirror connections read the help under &quot;<i>Add connection</i>&quot;
and see <a class="western" href="http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Juggluco/mmol.html#mirror">http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Juggluco/mmol.html#mirror</a></p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="addconnection" >
<![CDATA[
<h1>Add connection</h1>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Specify a connection
with another instance of Juggluco. Juggluco on one device sends via
IP/TCP data to a Juggluco on another device. To establish a
connection, one of the Juggluco\'s has to listen on a port and the
other has to make contact to that port. The port this instance of
Juggluco is listening on, was given in the previous screen (Left
middle menu-&gt; Mirror). Here you specify the port this instance of
Juggluco contacts to if it actively makes contact. If this instance
of Juggluco can\'t listen on a port, select &quot;<b>Active only</b>&quot;.
If the other side can\'t listen on a port, select &quot;<b>Passive
only</b>&quot;, otherwise leave &quot;<b>Both</b>&quot; checked. The
Juggluco on the other side should specify <i>Passive only </i>if you
select here <i>Active only</i> and <i>Active only</i> if you select
here <i>Passive</i> <i>only</i> and <i>Both</i> if you select here
<i>Both</i>.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">If this instance of
Juggluco actively makes contact, you should specify the IP(s) it
should contact with. If that host has multiple IPs, you specify more
than one; for example when two devices are sometimes connected via a
home network and sometimes directly as portable hotspot. Never
specify the IPs of multiple devices, in that case they will each
receive only part of the data. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">In all cases except
\'Active only\', you can select \'<b>Detect</b>\'; in this case Juggluco
saves the first IP contacting Juggluco as the IP of the other side.
Verifying if the right device is making contact can in two ways:
Select \'<b>Test IP</b>\' to test the IP. If you select <b>Test Label</b>,
a contact is only established if both sides have specified the same
label.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Select <b>receive
from</b> if you want this app to function as mirror app. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">If you want this
device to be the <b>sender</b> of data, you have to specify which
data to send.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Amounts</b>:
dose, food and sport data you have specified.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Scans</b>: data
received by scanning the sensor (scans and history).</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Stream</b>: the
data received by Bluetooth.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Sometimes some data
is already present on the receiving device. You can specify until
when this data is present:</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><i>Start: </i>no
data present</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><i>Now: </i>all data
present</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Or a specific date
determined by the begin position of the screen.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">When a data source
is added to an existing connection, the start date determined only
the added data source. For example if Scans and Streams were already
send to the host, and Amounts are now added, the start date only
determines the Amounts send. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">In case two devices
are connected via an insecure connection, data can be signed and
encrypted by specifying the same (maximal) 16-character <b>password</b>
on both sides of the connection. Select <b>Save</b> to save what you
have specified. <b>Delete</b> will delete this connection
specification.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">In the simplest
situation all connections belong to your home network, so you can use
local IPs. You can also connect over the internet via Wi-Fi, in that
case you should consult you modem manual on how to forward an
external port to an IP and port on you home network. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Two smartphones
connected via a mobile data connection over internet can directly
connect with each other, if one of them can listen on a network port.
If both can\'t (for example if neither has an individual IP), they can
still communicate with each other via a third device. One possibility
is to run Juggluco on an Android device (minimal Android 4.4) at home
connected to the internet via a modem. Another possibility is to run
a command line program belonging to Juggluco on a computer (e.g. your
PC or Amazon AWS):
<a href="http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Juggluco/cmdline/index.html">http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Juggluco/cmdline/index.html</a></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Port forwarding
tutorials:</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><a href="https://portforward.com/how-to-port-forward/">https://portforward.com/how-to-port-forward/</a></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><a href="https://stevessmarthomeguide.com/understanding-port-forwarding/">https://stevessmarthomeguide.com/understanding-port-forwarding/</a></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">It is possible to
receive glucose values via Bluetooth on a device without NFC (see
<a href="http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Juggluco/mirror">http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Juggluco/mirror</a>):
Initialize the sensor via NFC on the NFC device and then send the
Scan and Stream data to the non-NFC device.Hereafter reverse the
connection for Stream date and turn off the Bluetooth connection in
the NFC device and on in the none-NFC device and also turn off
&quot;sensor via Bluetooth&quot; in the NFC-device and on in the
non-NFC device. So you can scan with one device and get glucose
values via Bluetooth on another device. But on all devices all sensor
data should be available. If devices exchange data, they always
should receive both scan and stream data. So you should always send
the Stream data back to the NFC device and the scan data back to the
non-NFC device. Otherwise, the data will get out of sync leading to
old authentication data being used or new data being overwritten with
old data.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">The Amounts data is
totally independent.</p>
<h2 class="western">Network problems</h2>
<p>A strict complementary specification on both sides of the
connection is necessary. One simple omission can make data
transmission impossible.</p>
<p>It is possible that the connection hangs and has to be reset by
turning WIFI on or off or pressing Sync. Also, switching an
<i>activeonly-passiveonly</i> connection to <i>both</i> or the other
way around can make a difference.</p>
<p>For example a watch-phone connection using TCP over Bluetooth only
works if the watch is activeonly and the phone passiveonly. Over WIFI
it works in both directions.</p>
<p>You should also consider change of IPs with change of connection.
For example different IPs have to be used on the home network than
over a portable hotspot.</p>
<p><br/>
<br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="locationpermission" >
<![CDATA[
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">
Previously Juggluco needed location permission to find the Bluetooth
device address of FreeStyle Libre 2 sensors. Now Juggluco uses
another way to get the device address on most devices and is location
permission not necessary. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Juggluco still uses
the old method on Android 6,7 and 7.1 and location permission is
still needed for them.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="introhelp" >
<![CDATA[
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in">
<font color="#365f91"><font face="Cambria, serif"><font size="4" style="font-size: 14pt"><b>Juggluco</b></font></font></font>
is an applet for the control of blood glucose by people with
diabetes. It can scan Freestyle libre (1 and 2) sensors (via NFC) and
receive (via Bluetooth) glucose values from <font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Calibri, serif"><i><b>Freestyle
libre 2</b></i></font></font> sensors.</p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in">As the program is
run for the first time, you can (after initialization) scan a
Freestyle Libre <b>2</b> sensor by holding it against the NFC sensor
in your smartphone. Hereafter Juggluco will try to get a Bluetooth
connection with Freestyle Libre 2 sensors and receive every minute a
glucose value without scanning.</p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in">To take over an
activated FreeStyle Libre <b>3</b> sensor, you need to specify the
Libreview Account information you used to activate the sensor in
settings-&gt;Libreview, press &quot;Get Account ID&quot; and wait for
the Account ID to arrive before scanning.</p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">The
program contains four</span> <font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><font size="3" style="font-size: 13pt"><span lang="en-US"><b>menus</b></span></font></font></font><span lang="en-US">;
by touching on an empty part of the display you can open a</span>
<span lang="en-US">menu. Touch</span> <span lang="en-US">on the left
fourth</span> <span lang="en-US">of the screen opens the left menu,
the left side of the middle part opens the second</span> <span lang="en-US">menu
and the right part of the middle opens the third</span> <span lang="en-US">menu</span>
<span lang="en-US">and the right fourth</span> <span lang="en-US">of
the screen the fourth menu.</span> 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; orphans: 0; widows: 0; margin-top: 0.08in; margin-bottom: 0.08in; background: transparent; page-break-after: avoid">
<font size="3" style="font-size: 12pt"><i>Menu 4: Movement (right)</i></font></p>
<table width="96" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" style="background: transparent">
	<col width="96"/>

	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>15:10&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;6.7</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Search</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Date</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Day
			back</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr style="background: transparent">
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Day
			later</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Week
			back</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Week
			Later</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
</table>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">By
moving left and right over the screen you can move the curve left and
right. You can also move by using the </span><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><span lang="en-US"><b>movement
menu</b></span></font></font> <span lang="en-US">on the right. Use
</span><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><span lang="en-US"><i><b>Date</b></i></span></font></font>
<span lang="en-US">to select a date, </span><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><span lang="en-US"><i><b>Search</b></i></span></font></font>
<span lang="en-US">to search for glucose values and entered numbers.</span>
<span lang="en-US">The first item of the right menu is the current
time and by selecting it you jump to the right of the graph (now).</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in">If <i>manually scale
Glucose</i> is set in Settings, moving up and down in the upper part
of the screen changes the maximum of the graph, in the lower part of
the screen it changes the minimum. If <i>Manually scale Time </i>is
set in settings, you can increase or decrease the amount of time
displayed on the screen by changing the distance between two fingers.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; orphans: 0; widows: 0; margin-top: 0.08in; margin-bottom: 0.08in; background: transparent; page-break-after: avoid">
<font size="3" style="font-size: 12pt"><i>Menu 3: Display</i></font></p>
<table width="138" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">
	<col width="138"/>

	<tr>
		<td width="138" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Last
			Scan</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="138" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Scans&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;[x]</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="138" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Stream&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;[x]</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="138" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>History&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;[x]</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="138" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Amounts&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;[x]</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="138" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Meals&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;[&nbsp;&nbsp;]</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="138" height="37" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>
			Dark mode&nbsp;&nbsp;[&nbsp;&nbsp;]</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
</table>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">The
</span><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><span lang="en-US"><b>right
of the middle menu</b></span></font></font> <span lang="en-US">contains
display options. To view the last scan, touch the first</span> <span lang="en-US">item.
</span>A cross after <i>Scans</i> means that scans are displayed in
the graph. A scan is the current glucose value you get when you scan
your sensor. Scanning also transfers 15 minutes measurements of the
last 8 hours from sensor to smartphone. Display of these values can
be controlled by touching <i>History</i>. <i>Stream</i> stands for
glucose values send every minute via Bluetooth from a Freestyle libre
2 sensor to this applet. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in">You can enter all
kind of numbers (with whatever label you like) to document you
insulin, carbohydrate and activities. They are displayed at fixed
height in the glucose graph at the specified time and date. <span lang="en-US">Touching
on points</span> <span lang="en-US">in the graph or an entered number
gives information about that item. You can edit an entered number by
long touching it. Editing is also possible via the number list in the
left middle menu</span> <span lang="en-US">and touching the
corresponding data element.</span> <i>Amounts</i> determines the
display of entered numbers. In Settings, you can specify which labels
you like to use for these numbers. Above one of the numbers the
corresponding label is shown.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; orphans: 0; widows: 0; margin-top: 0.08in; margin-bottom: 0.08in; background: transparent; page-break-after: avoid">
<font size="3" style="font-size: 12pt"><i>Menu 2: Left of middle</i></font></p>
<table width="96" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">
	<col width="96"/>

	<tr>
		<td width="96" height="37" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p align="left">
			Notify&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;[&nbsp;]</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Export</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Mirror</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>New
			Amount</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>List</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Statistics</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
</table>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in">You can enter these
numbers by touching <i><b>New Amount</b></i> in <font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><span lang="en-US"><b>left
of the middle menu</b></span></font></font>. <font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><span lang="en-US"><b>Export</b></span></font></font>
<span lang="en-US">saves data in .tsv (tab separated values) format
to a file. </span><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><span lang="en-US"><b>Mirror</b></span></font></font>
<span lang="en-US">makes it possible to send data via IP/TCP to this
app running on a different device to display the same information.
With </span><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><span lang="en-US"><b>Notify</b></span></font></font>
checked, <span lang="en-US">every incoming glucose value generates an
Android notification. This notification is sent to some smartwatches,
so that you can see your current glucose value</span> <span lang="en-US">on
your watch. A version of Juggluco runs on WearOS watches. For certain
Garmin smartwatches with touch screen there is also</span> <span lang="en-US">a
watch app</span> <span lang="en-US">(called Kerfstok, see
<a href="https://apps.garmin.com/en-US/apps/b6348ccc-86d8-4780-8013-d9e19fed5260">https://apps.garmin.com/en-US/apps/b6348ccc-86d8-4780-8013-d9e19fed5260</a>),
that communicates with Juggluco, receives and displays the current
glucose value and can be used to enter</span> <span lang="en-US">amounts.
</span><span lang="en-US"><b>List </b></span><span lang="en-US">gives
a list of the entered numbers. If Juggluco has received enough
glucose values via Bluetooth, you can see some statistics by touching
</span><span lang="en-US"><b>Statistics</b></span><span lang="en-US">.
It shows the percentage of the measurements in certain glucose
ranges, the Glucose Management Indicator (a predictor of HbA1c),
glucose variability and a summary graph showing the glucose value
below which 100%,95%,75%,50%,25% and 0% of the values lie at each
moment of the day.</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; orphans: 0; widows: 0; margin-top: 0.08in; margin-bottom: 0.08in; background: transparent; page-break-after: avoid">
<font size="3" style="font-size: 12pt"><i>Menu 1: Left</i></font></p>
<table width="96" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">
	<col width="96"/>

	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>System
			UI&nbsp;&nbsp;[&nbsp;]</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Watch</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Sensor</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" height="26" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>
			Settings</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" height="26" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>
			About</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td width="96" valign="top" style="border: none; padding: 0in"><p>Close</p>
		</td>
	</tr>
</table>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">In
the </span><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><span lang="en-US"><b>left
menu</b></span></font></font><span lang="en-US">, you can find
</span><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><span lang="en-US"><b>Settings</b></span></font></font><span lang="en-US">,
to set the glucose unit to mmol/L or mg/dL, to</span> <span lang="en-US">specify</span>
<span lang="en-US">labels, set glucose alarms and medication
reminders</span> <span lang="en-US">and display ranges. System UI
determines if android controls and status bar are shown. Close can be
used to exit</span> <span lang="en-US">Juggluco.</span></p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="searchhelp" >
<![CDATA[
<h1>Search</h1>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in">Search can be used
to find glucose values and entered numbers.</p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">You
search for values </span><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><font size="3" style="font-size: 13pt"><span lang="en-US"><b>between
the given numbers</b></span></font></font></font><span lang="en-US">.
For example: 10 â€“ 999 to search for values between 10 and 999.</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in">Glucose values are
separated in Scan, History and Stream.</p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in"><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><font size="3" style="font-size: 12pt"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.8pt"><span lang="en-US"><i>Scan</i></span></span></font></font></font><span lang="en-US">:
value shown immediately after scanning.</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in"><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><font size="3" style="font-size: 12pt"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.8pt"><span lang="en-US"><i>History</i></span></span></font></font></font><span lang="en-US">:
Periodic measurements saved on the sensor and transferred to this
app. Freestyle Libre 2 sensors save every 15 minute a value and
transfer them by NFC to this app. Freestyle Libre 3 sensors, save
every 5 minutes a value and transfer them via Bluetooth.</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in"><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><font size="3" style="font-size: 12pt"><span style="letter-spacing: 0.8pt"><span lang="en-US"><i>Stream</i></span></span></font></font></font><span lang="en-US">:
1 minute periodic measurements send by Bluetooth from the Freestyle
libre 2 sensor to this app.</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">If
you have entered insulin, consumption</span> <span lang="en-US">or
activity data, you can search for them by selecting the corresponding
</span><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><font size="3" style="font-size: 13pt"><span lang="en-US"><b>label</b></span></font></font></font>
<span lang="en-US">in the spinner and specify the range of numbers
interested in: for example cycling between 50 and 100.</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">You
can also specify the </span><font color="#365f91"><font face="Cambria, serif"><font size="4" style="font-size: 14pt"><span lang="en-US"><b>time
of day</b></span></font></font></font> <span lang="en-US">you are
interested in. If you are interested in hypos between 22:00 in the
evening and 07:00 in the morning, you press on the first time </span><span lang="en-US">display
</span><span lang="en-US">(displayed 00:00 at start) and change it to
22:00 and change the second </span><span lang="en-US">time display </span><span lang="en-US">to
07:00 (You also have to select Stream and/or History and specify a
value range from 0 to 3.9 mmol/L (70 mg/dL)).</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">Touching
an </span><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><span lang="en-US"><b>arrow</b></span></font></font>
<span lang="en-US">starts searching in the given direction. </span>
</p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in"><font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><font size="3" style="font-size: 13pt"><span lang="en-US"><b>Reset</b></span></font></font></font>
<span lang="en-US">sets all search values to what they were at start.</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">In
</span><span lang="en-US"><i>Settings</i></span> <span lang="en-US">under
</span><span lang="en-US"><i>number labels </i></span>you can select
which label (e.g. <i>Carbohydra</i>) is associated with meals. If you
select this label in <i>&quot;New Amount&quot; </i>a <i>&quot;Meal&quot;</i>
button emerges. After touching, you can enter a meal out of its
ingredients. If you select this label here in the spinner, a box
emerges at the top of the screen where you can specify an ingredient
to search for and optionally the minimal amount of that ingredient.</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="shortcuthelp" >
<![CDATA[
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.14in"><font color="#365f91"><font face="Cambria, serif"><font size="4" style="font-size: 14pt"><b>Shortcuts</b></font></font></font>
can be used in Kerfstok.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.14in">In the number input screen on the
watch you can get to the shortcuts screen (on my Vivoactive 3 watch
by swiping to the left). Here you see a list of labels; pressing on
one of them inserts a corresponding value in the number screen. The
values can be numbers or arithmetic operators in combinations with
numbers e.g. *0.5 to multiply with 0.5.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.14in">Here in the setting menu you can
create, remove and edit these shortcuts.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.14in">A <font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><font size="3" style="font-size: 13pt"><b>list</b></font></font></font>
of existing shortcuts is displays on the left, after touching one of
them, a display appears where you can delete the shortcut, or change
the label or the value.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.14in">A new shortcut is created with <font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><font size="3" style="font-size: 13pt"><b>New</b></font></font></font>.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.14in">Changes are only saved after
pressing the <font color="#4f81bd"><font face="Cambria, serif"><font size="3" style="font-size: 13pt"><b>Save</b></font></font></font>
button.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0.14in"><br/>
<br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="labelhelp" >
<![CDATA[
<h1>Labels for amounts</h1>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in; line-height: 115%">Here you can create,
delete and modify labels for quantities added to the graph to specify
insulin, carbohydrate or physical activity. If you have already saved
some quantities, they will get the label corresponding to their
position. So if you give the second position another name, already
saved quantities specified with a previous name in the second
position will get that name.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in; line-height: 115%">To modify a label,
touch it.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in; line-height: 115%"></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in; line-height: 115%">After <b>Meal, </b>you
can select which label stands for the carbohydrate content of meals.
For that label in &quot;<i>New amount</i>&quot; in the Left middle
menu a <b>Meal</b> button is added, by which you can specify a meal
from their ingredients. The carbohydrate sum is than saved under this
label and you can later view this meal by selecting the Meal of a
saved value.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in; line-height: 115%"><br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="settinghelp" >
<![CDATA[
<h1 class="western">Settings</h1>
<h2 class="western">Unit</h2>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Select whether
glucose values should be given in mmol/L or dm/dL.</p>
<h2 class="western">Graph range: low-high.</h2>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Give a low and high
value, so that the bottom of the screen correspondents to the lowest
and the top to the highest. These values are only used when all the
glucose values displayed on the screen are within these bounds.
Otherwise, the bounds are widened so that all values are visible.
When you take 3 mmol/L (54 mg/dL) and 9 mmol/L (162 mg/dL), and all
the values on the visible display are between 5 mmol/L and 6 mmol/L,
the graph displays a glucose axis from 3 to 9. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">If <b>Manually scale
Glucose</b> is turned on, you can change this: moving your finger
over the top of the screen, moves the top half of the graph up and
down; moving over the bottom of the screen moves the bottom half of
the graph up and down.</p>
<h2 class="western">Target range: low-high</h2>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">The higher side of
the display is colored differently so you can see high values easier.
The same is true for low values. A red line is displayed to show the
too low side of the display.</p>
<h2 class="western">Glucose-axis numbers LEFT</h2>
<p>Place the numbers of the glucose level in the graph on the left of
the screen. Useful if you want to place your current glucose in the
middle of the screen, for example in Wear OS.</p>
<h2 class="western">Invert screen</h2>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Turn the display
upside down. It is switch on by default, because otherwise I did now
and then accidentally touch OK while scanning a sensor.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Some people ask for
portrait mode, but I have turned that off, because it is totally
inappropriate for the display of the glucose graph.</p>
<h2 class="western">Nfc sound</h2>
<p>Make sound during scanning in addition to vibration.</p>
<h2 class="western">Scanning starts app</h2>
<p>If checked this app will be started when you scan a sensor via NFC
even if this app is not displayed. If multiple apps have this
setting, android will display a chooser from which to select which
app you want to use. Somehow choosing one doesn\'t work and selecting
one to be chosen the next time neither. So in this case you can\'t
scan without an app in the foreground. Turning it off in this app,
will make it possible that at least one app can be activated this
way.</p>
<p>If you have root access, you can also disable NFC activation of
Abbott\'s Librelink app (doesn\'t work with Libre3):</p>
<p>Become root in adb shell or termux, and type:</p>
<p>pm disable
com.freestylelibre.app.nl/com.librelink.app.ui.common.NFCScanActivity</p>
<p>On Librelink 2.7.1 and lower you had to press:</p>
<p>pm disable
com.freestylelibre.app.nl/com.librelink.app.ui.common.ScanSensorActivity</p>
<p><span lang="en-US">com.freestylelibre.app.nl is here the Dutch
version of Librelink, this should be replaced with the version you
are using. You can find its name by typing</span> <span lang="en-US">(even
without root):</span></p>
<p>pm list package freestylelibre</p>
<p>Afterwards, you can still use Librelink for scanning when it is in
the foreground, but it will not be started otherwise. Librelink 2.5.2
and higher crash themselves if they detect root. But in Magisk you
can easily hide root by renaming Magisk and adding individual apps to
the denylist (Magisk 24.3) or Magiskhide (Magisk 23.0). You should
also add Juggluco to the denylist. Except when you use US Freestyle
Libre 2 sensors, you can also use an older version of Librelink
without root check.</p>
<p>Without root, under adb shell, you can also disable the whole app:</p>
<p>pm disable-user --user 0 com.freestylelibre.app.nl</p>
<p>Before calling Abbott customer service, you can re-enable it with:</p>
<p>pm enable com.freestylelibre.app.nl</p>
<h2 class="western">Libreview</h2>
<p>Connect with Libreview to send Freestyle Libre 2 and 3 glucose
values and amounts to Libreview and to get the account id used during
Freestyle Libre 3 sensor activation. Touch to change settings.</p>
<h2 class="western">Librelink broadcast</h2>
<p>Use the Librelink broadcast (originally send by the patched German
Librelink app 2.3.0), to send the Bluetooth glucose stream data every
minute to xDrip. In xDrip you need to set Libre2 (patched App) as
hardware data source. The glucose values displayed in xDrip are
different from the values it receives. For some reason xDrip only
updates its value every 5 minutes, probably because it was made for
devices that send only once per 5 minutes (A watch face connected to
xDrip regularly displayed more than 9 minute old values.) In
addition, xDrip displays its own interpretation of received glucose
values. Mirror devices can also sent to xDrip.</p>
<p>See <a href="https://github.com/jakobheyman/xdripJH">https://github.com/jakobheyman/xdripJH</a>
for an attempt to update the glucose value of xDrip every minute.</p>
<p>Freestyle Libre 3 sensors send missed values after a disconnection
period. These values are not sent with this broadcast. You will
receive them if you turn on the Web server in Juggluco and make xDrip
a Nightscout follower of Juggluco. Nightscout server:
http://127.0.0.1:17580</p>
<p>Juggluco can also directly contact with xDrip watch apps, so that
the watch app displays more recent glucose values. To use this
feature check <i>&quot;xDrip webserver&quot;</i> in the left menu
under <b>Watch</b>. See Help under left menu-&gt;watch for more
information. Only one app can listen to the network port used by the
xDrip webserver, so you need to turn off &quot;<i>xDrip webservice</i>&quot;
in xDrip itself if you want to make use of the one in Juggluco.</p>
<h2 class="western">xDrip broadcast</h2>
<p>Send the same broadcast as turned on in xDrip with
&quot;<i>Settings-&gt;Inter-app settings-&gt;Broadcast locally&quot;</i>
(com.eveningoutpost.dexdrip.BgEstimate). Apps like AndroidAPS listen
to it. Apps targeting Android 11 or higher need to add the following
to AndroidManifest.xml for it to work: 
</p>
<p>&lt;queries&gt; <br/>
&nbsp;&nbsp; &lt;package
android:name=&quot;tk.glucodata&quot;/&gt; <br/>
&lt;/queries&gt; 
</p>
<p>Every minute Juggluco sends a glucose value to all apps listening
to this broadcast, xDrip only to a few well known applications,
except when you explicitly specify the name.</p>
<h2 class="western">Glucodata broadcast</h2>
<p>A new broadcast that has the same function as the xDrip broadcast.
A simple example app that writes received glucose values to logcat
you can find here: <a href="http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Juggluco/glucosebroadcast.html">Glucose
broadcasts</a>. If you specify Juggluco as data-source in G-Watch,
you need to turn on this broadcast.</p>
<p>The application apps listening to this broadcast are shown. Check
the apps you want to send this broadcast to.</p>
<h2 class="western">Web server</h2>
<p>Web server that can be used with xDrip watches and some Nightscout
apps. Previously called xDrip webserver.</p>
<h2 class="western">Uploader</h2>
<p>Upload to a Nightscout server.</p>
<h2 class="western">Glucose in android status bar</h2>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">If set, glucose
values streaming via Bluetooth are quietly displayed in a
notification and the android status bar. If you turn it off, instead
of a number, a dot is shown and the notification tells nothing more
than &quot;<i>To connect to sensor</i>&quot; or &quot;<i>To exchange
data</i>&quot;. An app that stays running in the background, is
obliged by Android to have such visible notification (otherwise it is
easily stopped by Android). Juggluco only turns off the notification,
when &quot;<i>Sensor via Bluetooth</i>&quot; is turned off and there
are no mirror connections.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">On some smartphones,
the glucose value is only shown in the Android status bar after
changing Androids notification settings. On Realme GT 5G for example,
you have to go to applist-&gt;Juggluco-&gt;manage notifications, tab
on glucoseNotification and turn off &quot;Set to Silent&quot;.
&quot;Display in status bar&quot; will now be shown turned on.</p>
<p style="font-weight: normal; line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">
You can also get an android notification by selecting <i>Notify</i>
in the left middle menu. In that case the notification will be sent
to some smartwatches, if it is configured that way. That works with
Garmin watches, I don\'t know if it works with anything else. Alarms
also generate notifications.</p>
<h2 class="western">Floating glucose</h2>
<p>When you turn this on, a small image with the current glucose
value is constantly present on the screen independent of which app is
in the foreground. If you turn it on the first time, you will be
directed to a list of apps in which you have to give Juggluco
permission to <b>display over other apps</b>.</p>
<h2 class="western">Config</h2>
<p>Specify font size and colors of <i>Floating glucose</i> value.</p>
<h2 class="western">Sensor via Bluetooth</h2>
<p>Selects whether this app connects via Bluetooth with a Freestyle
libre 2 or 3 sensor. This is needed for alarms and continual glucose
monitoring.</p>
<h2 class="western"><b>Alarms</b></h2>
<p style="font-weight: normal">Set high en low glucose alarms, loss
of signal alarm and value available notification.</p>
<h2 class="western">Number Labels</h2>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Specify the labels
used for amounts. Go to a screen to determine which labels to use to
set amounts, like insulin doses, carbohydrate consumption and hours
spend playing football. If you also use the Garmin watch app
Kerfstok, these labels are sent to the watch app.</p>
<h2 class="western">Reminders</h2>
<p style="font-weight: normal; line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">
Specify that an alarm should go of if you didn\'t enter a certain
amount of food or medication within a certain time period.</p>
<h2 class="western">Colors</h2>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Change colors of
curves, scans and numbers.</p>
<h2 class="western"><br/>
<br/>

</h2>
]]>
</string>
<string name="sensorhelp" >
<![CDATA[
<h1>Sensor</h1>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">The spinner contains
the name of the sensor. If Juggluco is using more than one sensor at
the same time, you can select for which sensor to show information.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><i><b>Doze mode</b></i>
leads you to a screen with information on how to disable battery
optimizations for Juggluco, that can prevent Juggluco from
functioning.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><i><b>Permission</b></i>:
Previous versions of Juggluco required location permission to find
the device address of the sensor. This is no longer necessary for the
sensors I use. Maybe there are still sensors out there for which it
is necessary; in that case you can turn it on. After the first
contact Juggluco saves the device address and location permission is
always useless. The device address, if known, is displayed after the
sensor identifier. Red means a US-like sensor.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Android 12 has a new
Nearby devices permission, which can be used instead of location
permission for searching for a Bluetooth device address, but it is
also needed for later contact with Bluetooth devices.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><i><b>Wakelock</b></i>:
Some users of Android 13 complain that Bluetooth stops functioning.
Possibly turning this option on helps them. On my smartphone I don\'t
need it and on Watch4 it doesn\'t make a difference. If it works, it
will increase battery usage.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><i><b>Terminate</b></i>:
stop connecting to this sensor via Bluetooth. If later you want again
receive stream glucose values from this sensor, you only have to scan
it again.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><i><b>Turbo</b></i>:
Increases effort to contact with sensor in the hope that it results
in less connection errors, but can uses more battery power. Seems to
be needed on Watch4 with Freestyle Libre 2 sensors, but not with
Freestyle Libre 3 sensors and on none of the smartphones I tried it
on.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Android 13</b>:
Two users with a buggy Android 13 phone claimed that this setting
solved their Bluetooth connection issues. Two users with Android 13
who previous didn\'t have connection problems claimed that they got
connection problems from this setting.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><i><b>Info</b></i>:
Gives start and end times and last scan and stream times of sensor.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">To connect to a
Freestyle Libre 2 sensor via Low Energy Bluetooth, Bluetooth should
be turned on. Before the sensor is scanned successfully by this app,
nothing will happen. The sensor shouldn\'t be connected with FreeStyle
Libre reader or other applets on smartphones. Abbotts Librelink app\'s
alarms should be turned off or the app stopped. Some Librelink apps
seem to contact the sensor while alarms are turned off and can cause
connection problems, so use \'<i>force stop</i>\' to be certain. <b>Sensor
via Bluetooth/Use Bluetooth</b> should be turned on.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">If the above
conditions are satisfied, it can still take a long time before the
app receives glucose values from the sensor. Often it takes a minute,
but at other times it takes much longer. The <i>Connection stage</i>
gives the most difficulties. The most frequent are failures with
status=133, which is the status argument of
<a href="https://developer.android.com/reference/android/bluetooth/BluetoothGattCallback#onConnectionStateChange(android.bluetooth.BluetoothGatt,%20int,%20int)">onConnectionStateChange(BluetoothGatt
bluetoothGatt, int status, int newState)</a>. If you remove the
battery out of a sensor you also get this error, so it seems to be
something like <i>Bluetooth device not found</i>. Sometimes turning
Bluetooth off and on seems to help or rebooting the phone or turning
off the Bluetooth connection of other devices. Other problems are
sometimes resolved by scanning the sensor.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Scanning the sensor
with Juggluco (with <i>Sensor via Bluetooth</i> enabled) on another
phone, will steal the connection away from this phone and it can take
some time, with scanning in between, to get it back again.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="watchhelp" >
<![CDATA[
<h1 class="western">Kerfstok</h1>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">This view is used to
solve connection problems with Kerfstok
(<a href="https://apps.garmin.com/en-US/apps/b6348ccc-86d8-4780-8013-d9e19fed5260">https://apps.garmin.com/en-US/apps/b6348ccc-86d8-4780-8013-d9e19fed5260</a>
(see also <a href="http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Kerfstok/index.html">http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Kerfstok/index.html</a>).
Kerfstok is a watch app for programmable Garmin smartwatches with
touchscreen. Kerfstok has the following uses:</p>
<ul>
	<li><p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Enter numbers
	and exchange them with Juggluco;</p>
	<li><p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Displays the
	stream glucose value received from Juggluco;</p>
	<li><p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Displays this
	glucose value during sport, while also showing speed and distance.
	The activity will be recorded and can be displayed in Garmin\'s
	connect app.</p>
</ul>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">This watch app can
connect via Bluetooth with Juggluco to exchange amounts and
continually display your current glucose value. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">When a problem
arrives, can this screen help to find its cause:</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">First, your watch
name should be shown &quot;<i>CONNECTED</i>&quot;. If not, solve the
problem in Garmin\'s Connect app. Second, Kerfstok should be started
on your watch. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Sometimes the
connection between watch and phone is disrupted. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">If Send status is
FAILURE_DURING_TRANSFER, you can do one or all of the following:</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">- Switch Bluetooth
off and on, and thereafter press <i>Reinit</i>;</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">- Reboot the watch
(nearly always successful, but sometimes it has to be done multiple
times);</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">- Reboot the phone
(last option).</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">For other problems
force stopping the Garmin connect app, starting it again and pressing
reinit can be of use.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">If there is a proper
connection and for some reason the amounts on watch and phone are out
of sync, you can press <b>Sync, </b>to make them send the numbers
they haven\'t sent yet, to each other.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">On startup of
Juggluco, <i>Sync</i> is automatically called. This means that after
you reinstall Kerfstok, all numbers will also be removed in Juggluco.
The only way to keep these numbers, is to make a mirror and send it
back to Juggluco. Be careful because the mirror also is immediately
synced with its original. To function as a backup, all connection
with the original should be broken at some point in time. You can
also connect the watch to a device that is a mirror (left middle
menu-&gt;Mirror) of the device in which you entered the numbers.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Refresh</b>
rewrites this dialog with new information (e.g. after Reinit or
Sync).</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Checking &quot;<b>Glucose</b><b>&quot;</b>
determines if glucose values are sent to the watch.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Sometimes a button
named &quot;<b>Send Queue</b><b>&quot;</b> is shown; this means that
there are messages that are not yet sent to the watch. Normally they
will be sent automatically in due time, but sometimes this was
interrupted and pressing on <i>Send queue</i> will continue the
sending. But if it was not sent because of a broken connecting this
has very little benefit. Pressing <i>Send Queue </i>during an ongoing
transaction can break the connection.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="getlib" >
<![CDATA[
<h1>Libre Library</h1>
<p><font size="4" style="font-size: 14pt"><span lang="en-US"><b>Juggluco</b></span></font>
<span lang="en-US">needs a library included in </span><span lang="en-US">Abbott\'s
</span><span lang="en-US">Libre</span><span lang="en-US"> app</span><span lang="en-US">.
</span>
</p>
<p><span lang="en-US"><b>US Freestyle Libre 2 sensors </b></span><span lang="en-US">and
possibly sensors in other countries like Canada, need a library from
version 2.5.2, 2.5.3 or 2.7.1 of Abbott\'s Librelink app.</span></p>
<p><span lang="en-US"><b>Other sensors</b></span><span lang="en-US">
also work with a library from</span><span lang="en-US"> Librelink
2.4.0, 2.4.1</span><span lang="en-US"> or</span><span lang="en-US">
2.4,2</span><span lang="en-US">. </span><span lang="en-US">Versions
after 2.4.2 have become worse in terms of battery usage, and give the
same results</span><span lang="en-US"> in non US like Freestyle Libre
2 sensors.</span></p>
<p><span lang="en-US">The country code makes no difference.</span></p>
<p><span lang="en-US">The .apk containing Librelink is distributed by
Google Play and on all kind of places it is available on the web. A
list of links can be found at:
</span><a href="http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Juggluco/urls.html">http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Juggluco/urls.html</a></p>
<p><span lang="en-US">After you have downloaded the APK, you can let
Juggluco open it, by touching the </span><span lang="en-US"><b>Open</b></span>
<span lang="en-US">button.</span> 
</p>
<p><span lang="en-US">It is also possible to run Juggluco without
direct access to the Freestyle libre sensor. The app can get the data
via an IP/TCP connection from a smartphone that gets the data from
the sensor. Without access to the sensor, it is also possible to
enter diabetes control information, like amounts of insulin,
carbohydrates and activity and get this data from the Garmin watch
app Kerfstok. Touch </span><span lang="en-US"><b>Without sensor</b></span>
<span lang="en-US">to restrict Juggluco to this</span> <span lang="en-US">way.</span></p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="newlabelhelp" >
<![CDATA[
<h2 class="western">Label:</h2>
<p>Name of label to use to enter numbers. You can add a number linked
to a certain date and time by using &quot;New Amount&quot; in the
left middle menu. These numbers can be displayed in the glucose graph
at that time position or in a list.</p>
<h2 class="western">Round to:</h2>
<p>Used in watch app, Kerfstok. Numbers entered under this label are
rounded to this number.</p>
<p>0= full precision, 0.5 = round to multiples of 0.5 etc.</p>
<h2 class="western">Weight:</h2>
<p>When set to 0, numbers are displayed at a certain height in the
graph independent of their value. If weight is higher than 0, each
amount entered under this label is multiplied by this weight and
displayed as a square in the same coordinates as the glucose graph.
For example, you can set weight to 1 to display finger prick glucose
measurements the same way as glucose sensor measurements.</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="battery" >
<![CDATA[
<h1 class="western">Keep functioning</h1>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Normally when an
android device is not used, it enters doze mode to use less energy.
If you need to reliably receive glucose values via Bluetooth or
TCP/IP you need to switch off battery optimizations for Juggluco and
sometimes also the whole device to prevent that Androids switches off
Juggluco. A lot of devices have additional battery optimization-,
activity in the background - and start at boot settings that have to
be changed. You can find them under Android settings-&gt;Battery. See
<a href="https://dontkillmyapp.com/">https://dontkillmyapp.com</a>.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="nutrients" >
<![CDATA[
<p align="center" style="line-height: 100%; margin-top: 0.17in; margin-bottom: 0.08in; page-break-after: avoid">
<font face="Liberation Sans, sans-serif"><font size="6" style="font-size: 28pt"><b>Food
composition database</b></font></font></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">Here
you can lookup foods in the McCance and Widdowsonâ€™s The Composition
of Foods Integrated</span> <span lang="en-US">Dataset 2021</span>
<a class="western" href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/composition-of-foods-integrated-dataset-cofid"><span lang="en-US">https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/composition-of-foods-integrated-dataset-cofid</span></a></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">You
can search using regular expressions
(<a class="western" href="https://www.regular-expressions.info/quickstart.html">https://www.regular-expressions.info/quickstart.html</a>).
For example, you can search for items starting with </span><span lang="en-US"><i>apple</i></span>
<span lang="en-US">followed by the word </span><span lang="en-US"><i>raw</i></span>
<span lang="en-US">with: ^apple.*\\braw\\b</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Searching for <i>apple</i>
gives all items containing <i>apple.</i></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="mealhelp" >
<![CDATA[
<h1>Meals</h1>
<p>Specify the quantity of ingredients of a meal. The total
carbohydrate content is than calculated. It is also possible to
specify the amount of carbohydrate for the whole meal or the
ingredient and the program then determines the needed quantity of the
ingredient. Press &quot;<i>Add item</i>&quot; to add an item to the
meal. In the evoked dialog you can select an ingredient and specify
its quantity (or total carbohydrate of the meal or this item). By
pressing on <i>Select</i> or the already specified ingredient, you
come into a list of already defined ingredients. You can define a new
ingredient by pressing there on <i>Define</i>. Here you can than
specify the name and carbohydrate content of that ingredient in the
specified unit. You can also press <i>Database</i> to come in a food
composition database where you can search for ingredients and see the
composition of a food, and by pressing <i>Select</i> insert this
foods name and carbohydrate content in an ingredient definition.</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="colorhelp" >
<![CDATA[
<h1>Colors</h1>
<p>Here you can change the colors of numbers, curves and scan points.
Touch a point of a curve, scan or an amount (so that information
about that point or amount is shown). Hereafter touch a color in the
color view. The curve, scan point or amount will now be shown in that
color.</p>
<p>In the WearOS version you need a watch with a back key, swiping
back will not work.</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="stathelp" >
<![CDATA[
<h1 class="western">Statistics</h1>
<p>Some statistics taken from <a href="https://www.healthline.com/diabetesmine/ambulatory-glucose-profile">AGP</a>
without a license, with some minor modifications.</p>
<p>The number of days analyzed can be modified by pressing the <b>Days</b>
button. The period ends at the time of the end of screen position and
spans the specified number of days back in time. All data are only
based on glucose values received every minute via Bluetooth from the
sensor (called <i>stream</i> in Juggluco).</p>
<p>On the left of the screen are the percentage of measurements
falling in certain glucose ranges.</p>
<h3 class="western">% of the time active</h3>
<p>The percentage of time Juggluco received glucose values from the
sensor.</p>
<h3 class="western">Estimated A1C</h3>
<p>Estimates H<span lang="en-US">bA1c with an old formula from
average glucose (Nathan</span> <span lang="en-US">et al (2008)). See
<a href="https://professional.diabetes.org/diapro/glucose_calc">https://professional.diabetes.org/diapro/glucose_calc</a></span>
<span lang="en-US">for a calculator.</span></p>
<p><span lang="en-US">It is shown here in</span> <span lang="en-US">case
people are looking for the value shown in Abbott\'s Libre</span> <span lang="en-US">2
app. GMI is a 2018 replacement for this indicator. </span>
</p>
<h3 class="western">Glucose Management Indicator (GMI)</h3>
<p><span lang="en-US">Calculated from the average glucose with a
certain generally used formula (see <a href="https://www.jaeb.org/gmi/">https://www.jaeb.org/gmi/</a>).
It is an empirically determined prediction of HbA1c (also called
A1c), given in percentage and mmol/mol.</span> <span lang="en-US">For
me personally Estimated A1C is a better predictor than GMI, but it is
used in Abbott\'s Libre 3 app.</span></p>
<h3 class="western">Glucose Variability:</h3>
<p>The coefficient of variation (%CV), as a measure of glucose
variability. Higher values mean that the glucose level is less
constant.</p>
<h3 class="western">Summary graph</h3>
<p>(Only present when at least 9 days of stream glucose values are
available).</p>
<p>All stream glucose values in this period are taken to draw a
composite graph showing for every minute of the day how glucose
values were distributed. The black or white median line shows the
glucose value below which 50 percent of the glucose values lie at
each minute of the day. The lightest blue is the area in which all
values lie. Somewhat darker blue the area around the median wherein
90% of the values lie. The darkest blue the area around the median of
50 percent of the values. If you see the borders of the area\'s as
lines, you can also portray it as follows: Under the lowest line are
0% of the values, under the second lowest line (between the lightest
blue and the middle dark blue) 5% of the values, below the third line
(between the darkest blue and middle dark blue) 25 % of values, below
the black line 50% of values. Followed by 75%, 95% and 100%. 
</p>
<p>Out of aesthetic reasons the curve is smoothed with a binomial
filter.</p>
<p>Tap the screen to close the Summary graph, except that when
tapping the left or right border the graph moves backwards or
forwards in the day. The curve can also be moved back and forwards by
scrolling. The time scale can be changed by moving two fingers to or
from each other.</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="alarmhelp" >
<![CDATA[
<h1>Alarms</h1>
<h2 class="western">Glucose alarms:</h2>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">The stream values
received via Bluetooth can be used to set low and high glucose
alarms.</p>
<h3 class="western">Low glucose alarm:</h3>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Value below which an
alarm should go off.</p>
<h3 class="western">High glucose alarm:</h3>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Value above which an
alarm should go off.</p>
<h3 class="western">Loss of signal alarm:</h3>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Specify after how
many minutes an alarm should go off if no glucose value is received
via Bluetooth.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Alarms will <b>stop</b>
when one of the following conditions is satisfied:</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">- The specified
duration has elapsed;</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">- The curve view is
touched;</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">- The Android
notification of Juggluco is touched (in unlocked state);</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">- Cancel button is
touched of the alarm notification in Juggluco.</p>
<h3 class="western">Value available:</h3>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Sometimes the sensor
doesnâ€™t work. When you turn this on, you will be notified if the
sensor works again after a failed scan.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">For each alarm you
can specify which Ringtone to play and for how long.</p>
<h2 class="western"><br/>
<br/>

</h2>
<h3 class="western"><br/>
<br/>

</h3>
]]>
</string>
<string name="flashpermission" >
<![CDATA[
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">
It is sometimes claimed that the use of the Flash light requires
Camera permission on some smartphones. Because of that Juggluco asked
for that permission in previous versions. On the phones tested this
permission is not necessary and Juggluco doesn\'t ask for it anymore.
If Flash doesn\'t work or your smartphone crashes or behaves strange
when using Flash, you can try to turn it on.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">You can turn it off
again in the Android settings for Juggluco.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="nearbypermission" >
<![CDATA[
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">
Android 12 has some new Bluetooth permissions which require you to
give explicit consent for the use of Bluetooth. Old apps don\'t
immediately stop working, but you can now make use of these new
permissions. If you don\'t give this NEARBY DEVICES permission,
Juggluco can\'t receive Glucose values via Bluetooth from Freestyle
Libre 2 sensors. But maybe the old permissions still work.</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="watchinfo" >
<![CDATA[
<h1>Watch</h1>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Currently Juggluco
has four ways to get glucose values on your watch.</p>
<h2 class="western">Notify</h2>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">If
Notify is turned on in the left middle menu, an Android notification
is created every time a new glucose value arrives. Most</span>
<span lang="en-US">smartwatches can be configured to receive these
notifications. It works with Garmin watches. Some companion apps of
other watches don\'t send this notification to the watch, probably
because it is a modification of a notification that is constantly
present instead of creating a new notification.</span></p>
<h2 class="western">Kerfstok</h2>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">Kerfstok
is watch app by which you can enter numbers (like insulin doses)</span><span lang="en-US">,</span><span lang="en-US">
but </span><span lang="en-US">it </span><span lang="en-US">also
displays the current glucose value. Immediately as a new glucose
value arrives, Juggluco sends it to Kerfstok. So Kerfstok displays
always the most recent glucose value. Kerfstok can also record all
activities supported by Garmin and can display speed and distance.
See Watch-&gt;Kerfstok Status-&gt; Help and
<a href="http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Kerfstok">http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Kerfstok</a></span></p>
<h2 class="western">xDrip watch apps</h2>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">Juggluco
incorporates an xDrip webserver. This makes it possible to directly
use xDrip watch apps with Juggluco. xDrip displays a new glucose
value only every 5 minutes, while Juggluco displays a new glucose
value every minute. Juggluco also sends to the xDrip watch apps the
most recent glucose value. The glucose values are only send to the
watches if the watch app asks for them, thus how old the displayed
values are depends on when the watch app asks for them. For example
watch faces and data fields on Garmin watches only ask for a glucose
value every 5 minutes. Via xDrip this often let to 10 minute old
glucose values. When directly connected with Juggluco, these watch
faces show up to 6 minute old glucose values. Under </span><span lang="en-US"><b>Garmin</b></span><span lang="en-US">,
if you can\'t use Kerfstok, you have the following options to
regularly receive a recent glucose value. An xDrip widget
(<a href="https://apps.garmin.com/en-US/apps/73115e04-dc9f-4765-ad88-e7ae283ce995">https://apps.garmin.com/en-US/apps/73115e04-dc9f-4765-ad88-e7ae283ce995</a>)
can also be used during the recording of an activity. So if you have
a hand free, you can switch to this xDrip widget while recording an
activity with a standard Garmin sport app. There is also an xDrip
sport app that updates its glucose value regularly:
<a href="https://apps.garmin.com/en-US/apps/aaf6533b-bca1-4365-9131-9f882f6f148c">https://apps.garmin.com/en-US/apps/aaf6533b-bca1-4365-9131-9f882f6f148c</a>.
You can try to start at a moment, so that it will request a glucose
values just after it is available. Data fields and watch faces would
be the ideal solution, but restrictions imposed by Garmin make them
of little value. </span>
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">According
to a user there exist also a watch face for </span><span lang="en-US"><b>Fitbit</b></span>
<span lang="en-US">watches that works with the xDrip webserver:
<a href="https://glancewatchface.com/">https://glancewatchface.com</a></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">For
more information on the web server interface see
<a href="http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Juggluco/addwatch.html">http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Juggluco/addwatch.html</a></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>local only</b>:
only accept connections from localhost (127.0.0.1). If you turn it
off, also other hosts can access the server. If you don\'t configure
your firewall to redirect to port 17580, this will be only hosts on
your home network. This server uses only http. I made also a https
version, but that seems to be of no use without a certificate
specific for your hostname signed by a certificate authority. So I
left it out.</p>
<h2 class="western">Juggluco Wear</h2>
<p>There is a version of Juggluco ported to Wear OS. The display is
adapted to the smaller screen and a watch face is added. The watch
face can be installed as a usual Wear OS watch face and displays
beside the time also the current glucose value received via
Bluetooth.</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="wearosinfo" >
<![CDATA[
<h1 class="western">Wear Os</h1>
<p>A special version of Juggluco can run directly on a Wear Os watch.
It needs an Android smartphone with NFC to scan the sensor and via a
TCP connection this data is sent to the Wear OS watch. Hereafter
there are two possibilities:</p>
<ol>
	<li><p>The sensor stays connected with the smartphone and the
	smartphone sends every glucose value it receives via Bluetooth to
	the Wear OS watch via TCP;</p>
	<li><p>It is also possible to directly connect the sensor with the
	Wear OS watch. For this you need a Wear OS watch with good Bluetooth
	connectivity. 
	</p>
</ol>
<p>You can get Juggluco for Wear OS from Google Play on your watch.
Some pictures are shown at
<a href="http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/JugglucoWearOS/index.html">http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/JugglucoWearOS</a></p>
<p>To get it working do the following:</p>
<ul>
	<li><p>Ensure that both Bluetooth and WIFI are working on watch and
	phone;</p>
	<li><p>See that the watch has enough free storage space and RAM
	left. It is possible that Juggluco has to be reinstalled if the
	device runs out of storage space at a critical moment;</p>
	<li><p>Make the phone version of Juggluco working with the sensor.
	You have to scan the sensor a few times with &quot;Sensor via
	Bluetooth&quot; set. Receiving glucose values on the phone via
	Bluetooth is not necessary;</p>
	<li><p>Install the Wear OS version of Juggluco on your Wear Os watch
	and start it;</p>
	<li><p>On the phone go to left-menu-&gt;Watch-&gt;Wear Os Config.
	Your watch should be displayed in the spinner. Press &quot;Init
	watch app&quot;;</p>
	<li><p>If everything went well, in both Juggluco\'s a TCP connection
	is configured and all data on the phone is sent to the watch. This
	can take a long time if you were using Juggluco for a long time. You
	can check if the TCP connection is configured by looking in the
	Mirror dialog (phone: left middle menu-&gt;Mirror, watch:
	left-menu-&gt;Mirror). A connection with the same id as shown in the
	spinner for your watch should be shown. On the watch is should also
	contain the IP of the phone. If the are not there or the watch side
	doesn\'t contain an IP, press again on &quot;Init watch app&quot;. If
	it still isn\'t there, check the Bluetooth connection and the phone
	app responsible for the connection to your watch. (When the watch
	already has received data, pressing &quot;Init watch app&quot; has
	the effect of re-sending all, so you could as well re-install the
	watch version of Juggluco. Later on, if the right IP is not shown,
	you should on the phone turn the external connection (WIFI or Mobile
	data) off and on.</p>
	<li><p>If everything went well, the same data, as displayed on the
	phone version of Juggluco, is displayed on the watch version of
	Juggluco. Every new glucose value received by the phone is sent via
	TCP to the watch. Some settings like unit, glucose alarm levels and
	reminders are also transmitted to the watch. Later changes should be
	made on the watch itself. 
	</p>
	<li><p>If you have a smartwatch with good Bluetooth connectivity and
	you like to receive glucose values on your watch without having to
	carry your phone, you can connect the watch version of Juggluco
	directly with the sensor. After all values are sent to the watch,
	you can check <b>&quot;Direct sensor-watch connection&quot;</b>. By
	this, <i>&quot;sensor via Bluetooth&quot;</i> is turned off in the
	phone and turned on in the watch. The stream values are now sent
	from watch to phone as you can check in the Mirror dialog. You can\'t
	change &quot;Direct sensor-watch connection&quot; when watch and
	phone are not in sync.</p>
	<li><p>If you want to sent amounts from the watch to the phone, you
	should reverse the send-direction yourself in the Mirror dialog by
	unchecking it on the phone and checking it on the watch. On the
	phone &quot;<i>Receive from</i>&quot; should also be set. If
	everything isn\'t set exactly right, it doesn\'t work. &quot;Don\'t
	change amounts&quot; should be changed. The labels of <i>amounts</i>
	are always sent with the amounts. If you change the direction of the
	transmission of amounts from watch to phone, you can\'t change the
	labels. It shouldn\'t be too easy;</p>
</ul>
<p>If the sensor has a direct Bluetooth connection with the watch and
it\'s values are sent to a smartphone, scanned values should also be
sent from the phone to the watch and the stream values should be
synced before scanning the sensor with Juggluco (the settings are
configured automatically this way.) Otherwise, old values could be
sent back to the watch or modified authentication information is not
sent to the watch, which will result in <i>Unlock key</i> errors.</p>
<p>Changes to the connection should also only be made when the data
is synchronized; the data on phone and watch should be complete
copies (with the exception that you can leave out <span style="font-variant: normal"><span style="font-style: normal"><u><span style="font-weight: normal">all</span></u></span></span>
amount data).</p>
<p>The first time, when a lot of data has to be transferred from
smartphone to watch, you can attach the watch to the charger. My
watch turns on WIFI when it is attached to the charger.</p>
<h5 class="western">Watch-Phone connection</h5>
<p>At initialization, when all data are sent from phone to watch, you
need a Wi-Fi connection between watch and phone. Later data is sent
in small pieces via TCP. On my watch that is redirected through
Bluetooth, but only when the phone has an external connection, for
example Wi-Fi to your home network, a mobile data connection or a
portable hotspot. Otherwise the connection between phone and watch
stops after some time, because Wi-Fi is turned off by the system to
save battery power.</p>
<p>Juggluco itself detects the IPs of the other side, so you don\'t
need to set them. If you switch from Wi-Fi to mobile data, the IPs
are changed automatically. Sometimes you have to switch Wi-Fi or
mobile data off and on on your smartphone before it works (Juggluco
determines the IP at the moment Wi-Fi or mobile data is turned on,
but sometimes the IP is then not available yet.)</p>
<p>Automatic determination of the IP of the other side is specific
for the connection with a WearOS watch; for other Mirror connections
you still need to specify the IPs of the other side.</p>
<h5 class="western">Watch face</h5>
<p>Juggluco for Wear OS includes a watch face that shows your current
glucose level besides the time and up to four complications. To make
use of it you have to select this watch face for example in your
watch companion app under &quot;downloaded&quot;. Normally you will
see the last glucose value when the screen wakes up. When the display
is in ambient (always on) mode, the glucose value is only updated
when the minute indicator is increased or you press a button or raise
your arm. So the displayed value can be up to one minute delayed.</p>
<p>There is also a complication that uses the Glucodata broadcast of
the WearOS version to display the glucose value in every watch face
that accepts the complication:
<a href="https://github.com/pachi81/GlucoDataHandler/releases">https://github.com/pachi81/GlucoDataHandler/releases</a></p>
<p><br/>
<br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="about" >
<![CDATA[
<h1>About</h1>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Juggluco is written
by <a href="http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Juggluco">Jaap Korthals
Altes</a></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Besides the standard
Android libraries, use is made of the following:</p>
<ul>
	<li><p align="left" style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">NFC
	and Bluetooth commands</span> <span lang="en-US">specific to Abbott
	FreeStyle Libre sensors and interpretation algorithms specific to
	FreeStyle Libre sensors.</span> <span lang="en-US">All are
	undocumented;</span></p>
	<li><p align="left" style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">To
	communicate with Garmin watches use is made of<a href="https://developer.garmin.com/connect-iq/sdk">
	Connect IQ Mobile SDK</a>;</span></p>
	<li><p align="left" style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">The
	graphs are created with <a href="https://github.com/memononen/nanovg">NanoVG</a>;</span></p>
	<li><p align="left" style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">The
	mirror function uses <a href="https://ascon.iaik.tugraz.at/">Ascon
	authenticated encryption</a>;</p>
	<li><p align="left" style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Communication
	with Libre3 sensors uses <a href="https://github.com/intel/tinycrypt">TinyCrypt</a>;</p>
	<li><p align="left" style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">The
	color picker is an adaptation of <a href="https://github.com/yukuku/ambilwarna">AmbilWarna</a>.</p>
</ul>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Juggluco was
translated into Italian by <a href="mailto:matteo.gabriele81@gmail.com">Matteo
Gabriele</a>.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Juggluco was
translated into Portuguese by Rui Pinheiro.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Juggluco was
translated into Polish by <a href="mailto:adelis@translaris.pl">Arkadiusz
DeliÅ›</a>.</p>
<p align="left" style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="disturbhelp" >
<![CDATA[
<h1>&quot;<i>Do not disturb</i>&quot;
access</h1>
<p>In Juggluco you can specify for each alarm type whether it should
be played during &quot;<i>Do not disturb</i>&quot; (under Ringtone of
the specific alarm.) <meta name="created" content="00:00:00">On some
devices, alarms during &quot;<i>Do not disturb</i>&quot; mode are
only possible if Juggluco has &quot;<i>Do not disturb</i>&quot;
access. On pressing OK you will be directed to an Android setting
screen where you can give Juggluco this permission. Independent of
what you answer there, you can specify in Juggluco for each alarm
whether it should go of during &quot;<i>Do not disturb</i>&quot; or
not.</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="libreview" >
<![CDATA[
<h1>Libreview</h1>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Juggluco can send
glucose data and amounts to Libreview.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">If you use Abbotts
Libre app for Freestyle Libre 2 sensors, Libreview is based on the
history data out of the memory of the sensor. For this you need to
scan the sensor.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Juggluco uses the
stream data received via Bluetooth to create these 15 minute points
by averaging the stream values around each point. Now and then it
also sends an individual stream value in the same way as individual
scanned values are sent to Libreview by Abbott\'s Librelink app.
Juggluco doesn\'t need to be constantly connected to the internet for
all data to be sent to Libreview. Like the Librelnk app, it sends
data from the last 89 days to Libreview. What is necessary is that
Juggluco is constantly connected to a Freestyle Libre 2 sensor via
Bluetooth. For Freestyle Libre 3 sensors the 5 minutes history data
is used, so that all previous values are sent to Libreview. 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">To
make use of this service, you need to create a Libreview account at
<a class="western" href="https://libreview.com/">https://libreview.com</a>
and specify its E-Mail address and password here.</span> <span lang="en-US">Don\'t
send data from the same period multiple times to the same Libreview
account (for example from the Librelink app and Juggluco). You can
delete existing devices in Libreview in Account Settings-&gt;My
devices or you can take a new Libreview account.</span></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span lang="en-US">To
turn it on, you also need to check &quot;</span><span lang="en-US"><i><b>Send
to libreview</b></i></span><span lang="en-US"><i>&quot;</i></span><span lang="en-US">.
</span>
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Juggluco will send
new data to Libreview every time you switch away from Juggluco when
it wasn\'t done in the previous 20 minutes. You can also manually send
it to Libreview by pressing <i>&quot;</i><i><b>Send now</b></i><i>&quot;</i>.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Beside glucose
values, amounts can also be sent to Libreview. For this you need to
touch &quot;<i><b>Send amounts</b></i>&quot; and specify what each
label means.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Starting with
Juggluco 4.1.0 glucose values from FreeStyle Libre 3 sensors are also
send to LibreView.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Resend data</b>:
Start anew; resend data of the last 90 days to Libreview. You need to
press this when switching to a new Libreview account.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Result of the last
time trying to send to Libreview is displayed below the &quot;Get
Account ID&quot; button.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Because the values
sent to Libreview are first averaged over 15 minutes and then
analyzed, there can be small differences between the values shown in
Juggluco\'s statistics screen and Libreview. For example Libreview
says 100% of the time active, while Juggluco\'s statistics screen says
96.0%. Also some high and low values will be averaged away, so that
Libreview gives a somewhat higher <i>time in target </i>than the
statistics screen of Juggluco. Because the real history values are
less extreme than the average of the stream values around a history
value, this difference will be larger when Libreview is based on
scanned values.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Juggluco can be
connected with multiple sensors at the same time, while Librelink
only handles one sensor at a time. Juggluco also sends data from only
one sensor at a time to Libreview. It does this by first sending the
data from one sensor and only after no data is available from that
sensor, it sends the data from the following sensor. When Juggluco is
switched to a following sensor, Juggluco will not turn back to a
previous one, to imitate the one sensor policy of Librelink. This
means that when you run multiple sensors at a time and a later added
one ends earlier than an earlier added sensor, this earlier sensor
will send no data anymore to Libreview.</p>
<p><b>Get Account ID</b>: If you only want to receive the LibreView
account ID, but not send data to Libreview, you can fill in your
E-Mail address and Password and press on &quot;<i>Get Account ID</i>&quot;.
On the same line before this button, the Account ID will be shown
(this can take some time and the screen is not refreshed
automatically). Retrieving the Account ID from the LibreView server
makes it possible to use a FreeStyle Libre 3 sensor that was already
used with Abbotts Libre 3 app with this LibreView account. Starting
the sensor with Juggluco is reported not to work.</p>
<p><b>WARNING</b>: The Freestyle Libre 3 sensor should be activated
with this account.</p>
<p><br/>
<br/>
<br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="garminconfig" >
<![CDATA[
<h1>Kerfstok configuration</h1>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">The <b>source</b> of
Kerfstok can be downloaded from
<a href="http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Kerfstok/Kerfstok-source.html">http://jkaltes.byethost16.com/Kerfstok/Kerfstok-source.html</a>).
Users are free to modify it. Each watch app has a unique identifier.
If the identifier is different from the default, Juggluco needs to
know it to communicate with the watch app. To specify a different
identifier press <b>ID</b> and type the 32 character hex string.
Juggluco on one device can only be connected to one watch app on one
watch. Changes will lead to loss of data.</p>
<h2 class="western">Shortcuts</h2>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Shortcuts are sent
to the Garmin watch app Kerfstok to easily insert certain values.</p>
<h2 class="western">Dark mode</h2>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Specify if Kerfstok
should be white on black instead of black on white.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="librenumhelp" >
<![CDATA[
<p>Set &quot;<i>Send amounts</i>&quot;,
to send Amounts to Libreview. Before you can switch on &quot;<i>Send
amounts</i>&quot;, you need to specify for every label how the
amounts entered under that label should be sent to Libreview. The
labels themselves can be created, modified and deleted in Left
menu-&gt;Settings-&gt;&quot;Number Labels&quot;. 
</p>
<p>For labels send as comments to Libreview the following restriction
applies: after you change a label, will deletions and changes of
amounts entered under a previous label not result in modifications in
Libreview. For example, if you previously had the label Bike and
entered 20 then changed Bike into Cycling and modify 20 in 25, will
this change not result in a change in Libreview, but will both Bike
20 and Cycling 25 be present in Libreview. The only thing you can do
is to delete the current devices in Libreview and press on <i>Resend
Data</i> in Juggluco.</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="setlibrenumtype" >
<![CDATA[
<p>Select how the Amounts in Juggluco
entered under a particular label should be sent to Libreview. It is
possible to send more than one type of amount with the same Libreview
label. For example if you score Carbohydrate and pure Glucose food
under separate labels in Juggluco, you can specify for both that they
should be sent as <b>Carbohydrate</b> to Libreview.</p>
<p>For Carbohydrate, it is possible to <b>multiply</b> the amount
given in Juggluco with a certain number so that you can transform
other units into grams. If you count in Juggluco servings of 10 gram,
you can enter here 10, so that grams will be sent to Libreview.</p>
<p><b>Comments</b> means that the amount is sent to Libreview as if
you added comments in Librelink. If you specify comments here, the
Label plus the number entered for that label is sent. For example:
&quot;<i>Bike 50</i>&quot;, if you had a label &quot;<i>Bike</i>&quot;
and you entered &quot;<i>50</i>&quot; under that label. &quot;<i>Bike
50</i>&quot; will be shown under the graph of the &quot;<i>Daily log</i>&quot;
in Libreview at the specified time.</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="floatingconfig" >
<![CDATA[
<h1 class="western">Floating glucose</h1>
<p>Here you can set the font size and foreground and background color
of the floating glucose. You can also set background to <b>Transparent</b>,
making it invisible.</p>
<p><b>Touchable</b>: when set you can move the floating glucose with
your finger and remove it by long pressing it. When touchable is
unset, goes touch input to the window beneath the floating glucose,
so you can use the app under the floating glucose. You can also make
the floating glucose untouchable by <b>double tapping</b> it.</p>
<p>After typing the <b>font size</b>, you have to press the â€œ<i>Enterâ€,
</i>â€œ<i>Doneâ€</i> or &quot;âœ“&quot; -button on the soft
keyboard.</p>
<p>You can turn on and off Floating glucose with the â€œ<i>Floating
glucose</i>â€ checkbox in settings. You can also turn off â€œFloating
glucoseâ€ by <b>long pressing</b> on the floating glucose value. For
example when you have set the font size so large that you are not
able anymore to type a smaller font size on the soft keyboard.</p>
<p>To display over other apps Juggluco needs a special permission. On
WearOS and also Android Automotive you need to use adb to give this
permission:</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>adb shell pm
grant tk.glucodata android.permission.SYSTEM_ALERT_WINDOW</b></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in; background: transparent">
<br/>

</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in; background: transparent">
<br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="getaccountidhelp" >
<![CDATA[
<h1 class="western">Get Account ID</h1>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">How to get the
Libreview Account ID needed to for scanning a Freestyle Libre 3
sensor via NFC? If you specify &quot;<strong>Manual</strong><strong>ly</strong><strong>&quot;</strong>,
you can enter the Account ID manually. You can also unset â€œ<i>manually</i>â€
and press on &quot;<strong>From Libreview</strong>&quot; to use you
account e-mail address and password to receive it from Libreview.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">It is also possible
to receive the Libreview Account id from Libreview and thereafter set
&quot;<em>manual</em><em>ly</em><em>&quot;</em> and change the
Libreview account e-mail address and password. When you thereafter
set &quot;<i>Send to Libreview</i>&quot; and press &quot;<i>Resend
data</i>&quot;, data will be sent to that different Libreview
account, but the previous account ID is will still be used to scan
the sensor via NFC. This way, Juggluco sends data to a different
Libreview account than Abbotts Libre 3 app uses.</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="Nightscouthelp" >
<![CDATA[
<h1 class="western">Web server</h1>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Juggluco
incorporates a webserver by which other apps can receive glucose
values from Juggluco. It can be used by xDrip watches and some
Nightscout apps.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Using apps that are
made to make use of the xDrip webserver is relatively easy. Just
check active. Hereafter they can receive glucose from localhost on
port 17580. Nightscout server URL: http://127.0.0.1:17580 
</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Also some Nightscout
followers can make use of it. xDrip, Diabox and a <a href="https://github.com/dabear/FloatingGlucose/releases">Windows
Floating Glucose</a> app can be used with http when &quot;local only&quot;
is not set. On MacOS the same is true for Nightscout Menu Bar, Gluco
Status and Gluco Tracker (all in Apple Store). On IOS you can use
<a href="https://github.com/someoneAnyone/Nightscouter">Nightscouter</a>
also with http.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">If you want to
access Juggluco over the internet, you need to forward a port from
your modem. See:</p>
<ul>
	<li><p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><a href="https://www.makeuseof.com/tag/what-is-port-forwarding-and-how-can-it-help-me">https://www.makeuseof.com/tag/what-is-port-forwarding-and-how-can-it-help-me</a></p>
	<li><p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><a href="https://www.juggluco.nl/Juggluco/phones/index.html">https://www.juggluco.nl/Juggluco/phones/index.html</a></p>
	<li><p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Left middle
	menu-&gt;Mirror-&gt;Add Conection-&gt;Help</p>
</ul>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Other Nightscout
followers only make use of https and that requires that Juggluco has
an authenticated SSL key for the domain name used to access Juggluco.
If your external IP has an associated hostname, you can get a
certificate for free via <a href="https://certbot.eff.org/instructions">Certbot</a>
or <a href="https://www.sslforfree.com/">ZeroSSL</a>. You can\'t make
use of it if your external IP doesn\'t have a hostname. You can get a
free domain name from <a href="https://www.freenom.com/">https://www.freenom.com</a>.
I tried it, but within a few weeks without any notification they just
took the domain away from me and when I tried to register it again it
had a price. You can buy a hostname for a few Euro\'s a year (for
example from <a href="https://www.strato.nl/domeinnaam">https://www.strato.nl/domeinnaam</a>).</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">If you have received
the key files from an SSL authority, you have to give them to
Juggluco. The private key can be read in by pressing &quot;<em>Private
Key</em>&quot;, the Full Chain by pressing &quot;<em>Full Chain</em>&quot;.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">From ZeroSSL.com I
received three files: private.key, certificate.crt and ca_bundle.crt.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">private.key is the
private key, you have to give to Juggluco by pressing &quot;<em>Private
Key</em>&quot;.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">To make the full
chain, you have to concatenate certificate.crt and ca_bundle.crt.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Linux:</p>
<pre style="margin-bottom: 0.2in">cat certificate.crt ca_bundle.crt &gt;  fullchain.pem</pre><p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">
Windows cmd.com:</p>
<pre style="margin-bottom: 0.2in">copy certificate.crt + ca_bundle.crt  fullchain.pem</pre><p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">
Windows Powershell:</p>
<p>cat certificate.crt &gt; fullchain.pem<br/>
cat ca_bundle.crt &gt;&gt;
fullchain.pem</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">After using Certbot
I found the Private key in
/etc/letsencrypt/live/myhostname/privkey.pem</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">and the full chain
in /etc/letsencrypt/live/myhostname/fullchain.pem. &quot;<em>myhostname</em>&quot;
is the hostname I used.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">If you just want to
send glucose values from one Android to the other, you can better use
Juggluco\'s <a href="https://www.juggluco.nl/Juggluco/mgdL/index.html#mirror">mirror</a>
function (Left middle menu-&gt;Mirror).</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Android Aps and
Nsclient don\'t work as follower of Juggluco, but you can send glucose
values to them with the xDrip broadcast in Juggluco (left
menu-&gt;settings-&gt;xDrip Broadcast).</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">You need SSL for the
Android apps Diabetes:M, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=se.cornixit.nightwatch">Nightwatch</a>
and <a href="https://slingithub.github.io/CheckmateWeb">Checkmate</a>,
Sugarmate (MacOS) and <a href="https://github.com/JohanDegraeve/xdripswift">Xdrip4ios</a>.
Specify as Nightscout server URL: 
</p>
<p><i>https://hostname:port</i> 
</p>
<p><i>hostname</i> is the host name of the authenticated key you have
given to Juggluco, <i>port</i> is the port you forwarded to the port
you specified in this screen (default: 17581).</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">The web server can
also be run on a Linux computer. It will receive its data from a
<a href="https://www.juggluco.nl/Juggluco/mgdL/index.html#mirror">mirror
connection</a> from Juggluco connected to the sensor:
<a href="https://www.juggluco.nl/Juggluco/cmdline/index.html">https://www.juggluco.nl/Juggluco/cmdline</a>.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Another phone can
connect to this server via a mirror connection or as Nightscout
follower (for example on an Iphone). If there is a Nightscout app
that doesn\'t work with this web server, please tell me. Maybe it can
be made to work with a few changes.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>api_secret</b>:
Specify that followers should set the ap<span style="font-weight: normal">i</span><b>_</b>secret
http header element to this value. In Juggluco 4.9.1 or higher does
testing on this secret also work when the followers use this secret
as Nightscout token or use the api<b>-</b>secret header with an SHA1
encoded secret.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><strong>Visible</strong>:
Make Secret visible.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><strong>Port</strong>:
Specify the network port used to contact the https server. The
default is 17581.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><strong>Save</strong>:
Save modifications of Secret or Port.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><strong>Use SSL</strong>:
use SSL (https). For SSL you need to give a Private key and Full
chain for the host name used to contact this service.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><strong>Private Key</strong>:
select a file containing the private key. See above.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><strong>Full Chain</strong>:
select a file containing the Full Chain, see above.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><strong>Local only</strong>:
the http server can only be accessed with localhost. This doesn\'t
apply to https.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><b>Give Amounts</b>:
make it possible to receive the entered amounts using
<a href="http://localhost:17580/api/v1/treatments?count=3">http://localhost:17580/api/v1/treatments?count=3</a>.
(You have to specify for each label what has to be done with it. This
is also used for sending amounts to Libreview.) Via this interface
xDrip can receive Amounts from Juggluco. In xDrip you can do this in
two ways:</p>
<ol>
	<li><p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in">Take as
	&quot;<i>Hardware Data Source&quot;</i><span style="font-variant: normal"><span style="font-style: normal">,</span></span>
	<i>&quot;Nightscout Follower&quot;</i><span style="font-variant: normal">
	</span><span style="font-variant: normal"><span style="font-style: normal">and
	giving as â€œFollow URLâ€</span></span><i>,</i><span style="font-variant: normal">
	</span><span style="font-variant: normal"><span style="font-style: normal"><a href="http://localhost:17580/api/v1/treatments?count=3">http://127.0.0.1:17580</a>
	and check </span></span>â€œ<i>Download Treatmentsâ€.</i><span style="font-variant: normal">
	</span>
	</p>
	<li><p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span style="font-variant: normal"><span style="font-style: normal">Take
	another Hardware Data Source for example </span></span><i>Libre
	(patched app)</i><span style="font-variant: normal"> </span><span style="font-variant: normal"><span style="font-style: normal">and
	turn on settings-&gt;Cloud Upload-&gt;Nightscout Sync (REST-API).
	Enter as Base API URL, http://somekey@127.0.0.1:17580/api/v1/ and
	turn on &quot;</span></span><i>Download treatments</i><span style="font-variant: normal"><span style="font-style: normal">&quot;.
	Uploading to Juggluco is impossible, so this only downloads
	treatments and generates some error messages.</span></span></p>
</ol>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span style="font-variant: normal"><span style="font-style: normal">When
&quot;</span></span><i>Local only</i><span style="font-variant: normal"><span style="font-style: normal">&quot;
is unchecked, you can also use the home network IP of the phone
Juggluco is running on and, when you configure your modem to forward
to 17580 of that phone, the external IP of your phone. If you have
given Juggluco a Private Key and Full Chain for a hostname by which
the phone can be accessed and turned on </span></span><i>use SSL</i><span style="font-variant: normal"><span style="font-style: normal">,
you can also use that hostname and the Port you specified here, using
https instead of http.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><span style="font-variant: normal"><span style="font-style: normal">When
you want to upload treatments to Diabetes:M, you can either send
Juggluco\'s data to Libreview and save the data in Libreview with
&quot;</span></span><i>Download Glucose data</i><span style="font-variant: normal"><span style="font-style: normal">&quot;
and import this data in Diabetes:M with Data-&gt;Import from other
sources-&gt;Freestyle or get an authenticated Key for the external
hostname of you phone and give as Link external source, Nightscout
with as URL, https://yourhostname:Port, where yourhostname is the
hostname of your phone running Juggluco for which you have received
an authenticated key and Port is the port you mentioned here. It
doesn\'t seem to sync automatically, so in Diabetes:M you have to
press on Sync yourself.</span></span></p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><strong>Active</strong>:
Web server is running.</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
<p style="line-height: 100%; margin-bottom: 0in"><br/>

</p>
]]>
</string>
<string name="NightPost" >
<![CDATA[
<p>Upload to a Nightscout server. 
</p>
<p>In most cases you can also use the webserver in Juggluco or
<a href="https://www.juggluco.nl/Juggluco/cmdline">juggluco-server</a>,
only AAPS and NSclient refuse to work when not connected to
<a href="https://github.com/nightscout/cgm-remote-monitor">cgm-remote-monitor</a>.</p>
<p>AAPS doesn\'t work when not connected to a Nightscout server. If
the functionality of this Artificial Pancreas is really dependent on
a Nightscout server, they could better put the Nightscout server in
AAPS, rather than making it dangerously dependent on an internet
connection. If the core functionally of AAPS is not dependent on
Nightscout, they could better remove the obligation to make use of
this Nightscout server.</p>
<p>All stream values are uploaded to the Nightscout server at the
moment they arrive. When multiple sensor are used, all values of all
sensors are uploaded. Some Garmin watch apps/faces/widgets assume
that the values are space 5 minutes apart. When they receive glucose
values one minute apart, they will only show the last fifth of the
curve. For that reason, the webserver incorporated in Juggluco spaces
the values 5 minutes apart, except when &quot;interval=secs&quot; is
set to a lower value.</p>
<p><b>URL</b>: the url should be in the form of https://hostname:port
for example, https://myname.herokuapp.com:6789</p>
<p><b>Active</b>: Turn server on</p>
<p><b>Resend data</b>: Upload all data again to the Nightscout server</p>
<p><b>Send now</b>: Normally data is immediately send when it arrives
from the sensor or a mirror connection. Press on this button when for
some reason a previous attempt failed.</p>
]]>
</string>
</resources>
